Gijs Wels





05/29/1997



+31611856348



gijswels@gmail.com



Amsterdam



gijswels.github.io

Qualities

- ◆ Independant
- ◆ Team player
- ◆ Curious
- ◆ Creative thinking
- Solution oriented

Languages











Industrial Design Engineer

I am an industrial designer with a focus on physical products and the relationships we create between people and their world through design - the new behaviours and experiences they enable. I have a special interest in well-being, innovation, and good design, both aesthetically and practically. I learned that it is not only important to dream but also to realise. This results in a hardworking person who motivates those around him to achieve the same goals - to make things happen!

Education

MSc Integrated Product Design

May 29, 2024

TU Delft, Delft

» Product(-service) design and technical prototyping.

BSc Industrial Design Engineering

2021

TU Delft, Delf

» Technology, bussiness, people, and design.

Minor Architecture

2019

TU Delft, Delf

» House of the future, analysing global trends, and spatial design and planning.

VWO+ s.g. Spieringshoek, Schiedam

2015

Extracurricular

Ambassadeurs van Amsterdam

09/2024 - 12/2024

Amsterdan

» Tackling a societal issue, developing a project plan in a diverse group and running a pilot.

Summer School

07/2023 - 08/2023

Aalto University, Helsinki

Design environments in balance with nature in an international and multidisciplinary group.

Exchange

01/2023 - 06/2023

Chalmers University, Gothenburg

» UX, form & manufacturing, manufacturing strategy, and introduction in data science & AI.

Internship

09/2020 - 02/2021

DigiNova, Delf

» UX, UI, and development. A music application for robots for elderly with dementia.

Employment

Royal Ahrend

10/2023 - 05/2024

Office Furniture, Sint-Oedenrode

» Graduation project. Studying behaviour, work culture and employee well-being (stress).

MBO Rijnland

02/2019 - 06/2019

Secretary School, Goud

» Teaching assistent.

Frankeland

08/2012 - 02/2023

Nursing Home, Schiedam

» Host. Bridge between elderly and management.

Noteworthy Achievements

Micro-Break Communication Tool

Royal Ahrend, Sint-Oedenrode

By creating social awareness the goal is to counter the rising trend of burnout complaints.

Natural Seating

2023

2024

Aalto University, Helsinki

Seat to connect with nature; focus on functionality, minimalistic design and biodegradability.

I got selected by my faculty to participate in an international and multidisciplinary project about the use of wood in balance with nature.

High difficulty. An ergonomically almost impossible task, but I fondly look back on it. Ahrend

wants to release the chair in the future.

I graduated with a 9 out of 10 for my Master

thesis. I got selected to speak at the Vital Work

event hosted by the Workplace Vitality Hub.

Adjustable School Chair

Royal Ahrend, Sint-Oedenrode

Desk chair for Dutch primary education; adjustable to all students from the age of 5 to 12.

Adaptable City Square

2021

The Green Village, Delft

Of all thirty participating students, my solution got selected by the organisation to continue.

Bachelor thesis; green solution to the urban heat island effect in the municipality of Delft.















urban oasis





nature's seat



Skills

3D Modelling

Rhinoceros Drawing

Visual Communication

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Adobe Premiere

Digital Prototyping

Adobe Dreamweaver Figma Adobe XD Arduino Raspberry

Physical Prototyping

Rapid Prototyping Workshop Experienced

I know my way around

JavaScript Python Mathlab Arduino Raspberry Pi